Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010 TJU.2010.01.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Press Office, 1981-2005; IV.
  - Press Releases, 1981-2005; 1.
    - August-September 1983 (Box 1221, Folder 18)
      - Specter introduces comprehensive legislation to aid ailing coal industry, August 3, 1983; 5.
      - Specter introduces bill to facilitate reclamation of surface mines, August 3, 1983; 6.
      - Specter resolution would delay FCC increase in telephone rates, August 4, 1983; 7.
      - Specter criticizes federal inaction on coal mine roof accidents, August 8, 1983; 8.
      - Specter sponsors federal procurement conference for PA businessmen in Harrisburg on August 16, August 9, 1983; 9.
      - Specter bets mushrooms against steaks on outcome of Penn State-Nebraska game, August 18, 1983; 10.
      - Specter recognized as leading senator with blacks on congressional staff, August 25, 1983; 11.
      - Senator Specter's comments on downing of Korean airliner, September 1, 1983; 12.
      - Specter comments on President's speech, September 6, 1983; 13.
      - Specter announces U.S. Department of Transportation grants to SEPTA totaling $33.7 million, September 7, 1983; 14.
      - Specter expresses concern over reduction in level of OSHA enforcement activities, September 12, 1983; 15.
      - Specter bill would retain "institutional independence" of Civil Rights Commission, September 13, 1983; 16.
      - Specter urges House Ways and Means Committee to support extension of unemployment benefits, September 13, 1983; 17.
      - Specter bill would extend federal unemployment compensation for six months, September 15, 1983; 18.
      - Specter argues successfully for federal funding for a number of social programs, September 16, 1983; 19.
      - Specter urges extension of federal unemployment benefits; desperately needed in PA, September 16, 1983; 20.
      - Specter seeks drought relief for Pennsylvania farmers, September 18, 1983; 21.
      - Specter urges funding for Bureau of Mines to allow Carnegie Mellon University expansion, September 19, 1983; 22.
      - Specter gets assurances funding will be available to solve Centralia fire problem, September 20, 1983; 23.
      - Specter concerned about drought, plans to offer resolution directing President to appoint commission to help farmers, September 20, 1983; 24.
      - Specter gets Appropriations Committee to withhold part of funding to El Salvador until trials of murderers of American nuns is concluded, September 27, 1983; 25.
      - Specter supports war powers resolution after colloquy with Senator Percy clarifies issues, September 1983; 26.
      - Specter seeks assurances from Attorney General staff that Irish national Michael O'Rourke will not be deported before probe into his case is completed, September 29, 1983; 27.
      - Specter amendment to supplemental unemployment bill gives 10 extra weeks to railroad workers, September 30, 1983; 28.
    - October 1983 (Box 1221, Folder 19)
      - Specter offers modified sale-leaseback bill for elderly homeowners, October 3, 1983; 1.
      - Specter gets Senate to add $3.5 million to program for runways and homeless youth, October 4, 1983; 2.
      - Specter amendment to appropriations bill would provide $9 million to Penn dental school, October 4, 1983; 3.
      - Specter introduces bill to preserve Washington Square Park, October 4, 1983; 4.
      - Specter bill would provide short-term mortgage assistance to out-of-work veterans, October 5, 1983; 5.
      - Specter wagers Philadelphia scrapple against California oranges on the outcome of the Phillies-Dodgers championship series, October 5, 1983; 6.
      - Specter to inspect carrier Saratoga in Florida on Saturday; Anxious to keep carrier overhaul work in Philadelphia, October 6, 1983; 7.
      - Specter bill would provide federal aid to innocent victims of crime, October 7, 1983; 8.
      - Specter bets on Phillies in World Series, October 10, 1983; 9.
      - Specter urges colleagues to support funding for Centralia fire, October 12, 1983; 10.
      - Specter bill would authorize federal government to use volunteers to provide services, October 17, 1983; 11.
      - Specter urges Agriculture Department to increase its meat inspection force, October 17, 1983; 12.
      - Specter urges more federal surplus food for families of unemployed in Pennsylvania, October 18, 1983; 13.
      - Specter urges $850,000 more for design work for flood control project at Lock Haven, October 18, 1983; 14.
      - Specter urges immediate funding for replacement of locks on Monongahela River, October 18, 1983; 15.
      - Senate Appropriations, at Specter's urging, assigns $42 million for Centralia mine fire, October 19, 1983; 16.
      - Corps of Engineers okays Specter's bill for flood control on Susquehanna River in Wyoming Valley at Wilkes-Barre and downstream, October 24, 1983; 17.
      - Specter seeks federal funding for Pittsburgh's downtown expressway system, October 25, 1983; 18.
      - Specter amendment to fiscal year 1984 supplemental appropriations bills gives 10 extra weeks of unemployment benefits to railroad workers, October 26, 1983; 19.
      - Specter gets $5 million for Lincoln-Cheyney-Science Center joint project, October 26, 1983; 20.
      - Specter-Hawkins bill would vastly increase federal role in locating missing children, October 27, 1983; 21.
      - Specter statement on Senate action to provide $42 million for Centralia underground fire, October 27, 1983; 22.
      - Senate okays Specter-Pryor amendment for $40 million in emergency food and shelter for needy, October 27, 1983; 23.
      - Specter tells Senate hearing that his sale-leaseback bill needed by elderly homeowners, October 28, 1983; 24.
      - Specter criticizes weakened FTC policy on deceptive ads, October 30, 1983; 25.
    - November-December 1983 (Box 1221, Folder 20)
      - Specter says he now has 52 co-sponsors for congressional Civil Rights Commission bill, November 3, 1983; 1.
      - Specter bill would allow health insurance companies to work together in attempt to hold down spiraling heath care costs, November 4, 1983; 2.
      - Specter announces authorization for six badly-needed PA public works projects, November 8, 1983; 3.
      - Specter announces OMB releases $14 million to cover PA poultry farmers for losses, November 9, 1983; 4.
      - Specter bill would create seven new superior court judges for District of Columbia, November 9, 1983; 5.
      - Senate subcommittee grants Specter request for hearings into avian flu epidemic in PA, November 10, 1983; 6.
      - House-Senate conferees include $42 million for Centralia fire; Specter expresses "deep satisfaction", November 15, 1983; 7.
      - Specter-pushed emergency aid for the needy funded by House-Senate conferees, November 15, 1983; 8.
      - House-Senate conferees okay Specter amendment which gives 10 extra weeks of unemployment benefits to railroad workers, November 15, 1983; 9.
      - House-Senate conferees include $54 million for Specter-backed Agent Orange research, November 15, 1983; 10.
      - Specter bill renaming Altoona VA hospital for James E. Van Zandt passed by U.S. Senate, November 18, 1983; 11.
      - Specter-Heinz resolution granting citizenship posthumously to William and Hannah Penn is passed by the U.S. Senate, November 18, 1983; 12.
      - Specter urges Defense Department to meet its spending targets for high unemployment areas, November 22, 1983; 13.
      - Specter accuses Corps of Engineers of stalling on Presque Isle beach erosion project, November 23, 1983; 14.
      - Specter urges Army Department to provide adequate funding for Lock Haven flood control project, December 7, 1983; 15.
      - Specter, concerned about U.S. Steel layoffs, again urges President Reagan to support his anti-dumping legislation, December 28, 1983; 16.
    - January-June 1984 (Box 1221, Folder 21)
      - Specter asks Commerce Department not to close Philadelphia minority business office, January 3, 1984; 1.
      - Specter wants Pittsburgh minority business development office reopened, January 3, 1984; 2.
      - Specter bill would guarantee $12 billion annually from DOD for areas of high unemployment, January 23, 1984; 3.
      - Specter wants "full compensation" for PA farmers affected by avian flu epidemic, January 27, 1984; 4.
      - Specter asks for quick okay for study recommending replacement of two locks on the Monongahela River, February 1, 1984; 5.
      - Specter bills would speed up trials and reduce backlogs in court system, February 7, 1984; 6.
      - Specter asks President to extend invitation to perform at the White House to Lancaster, PA, classical piano duo, February 9, 1984; 7.
      - Specter resolution would designate October 7-13 as "National Birds of Prey Conservation Week", February 9, 1984; 8.
      - Specter bill would provide funding to community organizations for pre-vocational training, February 9, 1984; 9.
      - Statement of U.S. Senator Arlen Specter on death of Uri Andropov, February 10, 1984; 10.
      - Specter and son to defend U.S. at Cambridge University, England debate, February 10, 1984; 11.
      - Specter asks OMB to reinstate $18.3 million for VA center addition in Philadelphia, February 15, 1984; 12.
      - Specter and Foglietta announce MAC to come to Philadelphia; means $100 million for area, February 23, 1984; 13.
      - Specter's tough sentencing "career criminal" bill passed by U.S. Senate, February 23, 1984; 14.
      - Specter urges Mine Safely Administration to add inspectors, February 24, 1984; 15.
      - Specter tells the Senate Foreign Relations Committee that U.S. embassy in Israel should be moved from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem, February 28, 1984; 16.
      - Specter introduces bill to delay deportation of Irish national, Michael O'Rourke, February 28, 1984; 17.
      - Specter objects to movement of nuclear waste through cities: wants DOT to study alternate routes and to prepare impact studies, February 28, 1984; 18.
      - Specter asks AG to make public all evidence it had of safety rule violations at Three Mile Island, February 29, 1984; 19.
      - Specter supports bill setting quotas on steel imports, March 1, 1984; 20.
      - Specter urges immediate federal funding for Lehigh Valley highway project, March 1, 1984; 21.
      - Specter urges immediate federal funding for two "high priority" Allegheny County highway projects, March 1, 1984; 22.
      - Specter co-sponsors resolution naming May 25 as "Missing Children's Day", March 2, 1984; 23.
      - Specter receives Health Service Award from community health centers, March 5, 1984; 24.
      - Specter gets GAO report in urging more prison cells for violent career criminals, March 6, 1984; 25.
      - Specter and Clinger get extra $200,000 for Lock Haven flood control project, March 7, 1984; 26.
      - Specter bill would bring EPA and superfund into problem of cleaning up groundwater contaminated by leaking underground storage tanks, March 13, 1984; 27.
      - Specter urges speedy determination of mine subsidence problem at Dunmore, PA, so that corrective action can be taken, March 14, 1984; 28.
      - Specter will seek federal funding for repair of damaged levee at York, PA, March 15, 1984; 29.
      - Specter wants tougher safety standard for grain elevators than OSHA is proposing, March 19, 1984; 30.
      - Specter legislation would deter "predatory" takeover of large energy corps by closing tax loopholes, March 20, 1984; 31.
      - Specter testifies that his bill will give PA fair share of federal highway funds, March 22, 1984; 32.
      - Specter urges USDA to make supplemental payments to PA poultry farmers, March 30, 1984; 33.
      - Specter objects to proposed VA changes in educational payments to veterans, March 30, 1984; 34.
      - Specter-Heinz amendment will provide $3.4 million for Lincoln-Cheyney-Science Center educational center in west Philadelphia, March 30, 1984; 35.
      - Specter urges more defense spending in high unemployment areas, like PA, April 3, 1984; 36.
      - Specter testifies that oil mergers are adversely affecting public policy; says his legislation will stop them by closing tax loopholes, April 5, 1984; 37.
      - Specter-Heinz bill would designate 9,400 acres in Allegheny Forest in NE PA as wilderness area, April 10, 1984; 38.
      - Specter-Heinz amendment to provide health care for the unemployed is defeated, April 11, 1984; 39.
      - Specter disappointed by USDA payment to PA poultry farmers; urges "fair market compensation" as mandated by law, April 12, 1984; 40.
      - Specter's sale-leaseback bill for elderly and rural enterprise zones passed in Senate's comprehensive tax bill, April 13, 1984; 41.
      - Specter amendment to tax bill will save coal and iron ore industries $100 million, April 13, 1984; 42.
      - Specter urges immediate funding for Allentown, PA, highway project, April 18, 1984; 43.
      - Specter announces Navy to name cruiser for the late Thomas S. Gates, April 18, 1984; 44.
      - Specter says Congress should set "legislative policy" for movement of nuclear waste, April 24, 1984; 45.
      - Senators Specter and D'Amato and Mayor Koch to tour New York City prison on Saturday, April 27, 1984; 46.
      - Specter urges continued 80-20, federal-local ratio in funding for Johnstown's inclined plane; would save city $125,000, May 1, 1984; 47.
      - Specter urges no cuts in funding for programs that benefit farm and rural areas, May 2, 1984; 48.
      - Specter urges ITC to limit steel imports to 15 percent of domestic consumption, May 2, 1984; 49.
      - Specter urges funding for Monongahela River locks and dams and for Presque Isle, May 2, 1984; 50.
      - Specter to hold open houses in Harrisburg, Gettysburg, and York over the weekend, May 3, 1984; 51.
      - Specter proposes answers to crime problems, May 5, 1984; 52.
      - Specter wants $1.8 million for continued planning for Wyoming Valley flood control job, May 8, 1984; 53.
      - Specter-Grassley anti-child pornography bill passed by the House; goes to President, May 8, 1984; 54.
      - Specter wants ship overhauls of Inchon and Iwo Jima to stay at Philadelphia shipyard, May 8, 1984; 55.
      - Specter urges ITC to limit steel imports to save jobs of U.S. Steel workers, May 9, 1984; 56.
      - Senate Judiciary Committee gives its okay to the "Missing Children's Act", May 10, 1984; 57.
      - Specter urges U.S. DOT locate automated flight service station at Bradford, PA, May 11, 1984; 58.
      - Specter announces his intent to introduce legislation next week to require Presidents to seek congressional approval in advance before sending U.S. troops into combat, May 12, 1984; 59.
      - Specter introduces legislation to require Presidents to seek congressional approval in advance before sending U.S. troops into combat, May 15, 1984; 60.
      - Specter requests $500,000 for Presque Isle project planning and design, May 16, 1984; 61.
      - Senator Specter and Congressman Hughes announce formation of "Congressional Crime Caucus", May 17, 1984; 62.
      - Specter renews request that Inchon and Iwo Jima overhauls remain at PSNY, May 18, 1984; 63.
      - President Reagan signs into law Specter-Grassley anti-child pornography bill, May 21, 1984; 64.
      - Specter amends Agent Orange bill to make it easier for veterans to get benefits, May 22, 1984; 65.
      - Specter wins Senate funding authorization for Philadelphia VA hospital addition, May 23, 1984; 66.
      - Specter announces $8.188 million U.S. DOT award for new coast guard headquarters in Philadelphia, May 23, 1984; 67.
      - Specter "glad" justice finally achieved in El Salvadorian murder of four U.S. nuns, May 24, 1984; 68.
      - Specter testifies in support of his bill to create wilderness area in Allegheny National Forest in northwestern Pennsylvania, May 24, 1984; 69.
      - Specter wants more federal funds for job training, mine safety, runaway youth, and health programs in fiscal year 1985 budget, May 25, 1984; 70.
      - Specter wins funding for Pennsylvania public works projects on Monongahela River, at Presque Isle, at York and at Lock Haven, May 25, 1984; 71.
      - Specter seeks funding for wide variety of transportation projects in Pennsylvania, May 25, 1984; 72.
      - Specter urges full protection for El Salvadorian trial judge after published reports of threats to him and his family, June 4, 1984; 73.
      - Specter wins $300,000 for Presque Isle project in Appropriations Committee, June 5, 1984; 74.
      - Specter prevails on Assistant Army Secretary to take a first-hand look at problem of beach erosion at Presque Isle, June 4, 1984; 75.
      - Specter gets funding for Lock Haven and York flood control projects, June 5, 1984; 76.
      - Specter gets funding for continued work on locks and dams on Monongahela River, June 5, 1984; 77.
      - Specter wants diplomatic immunity from prosecution eliminated for foreign diplomats who commit crimes while armed, June 6, 1984; 78.
      - Specter urges more federal funds for coal research, and land and water conservation, June 6, 1984; 79.
      - Specter request gets EPA working on procedures to handle Giardiasis disease, June 7, 1984; 80.
      - Specter urges his colleagues to support quotas for foreign steel imports, June 7, 1984; 81.
      - Specter wins funding for missing children's act and additional funding for the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, prison construction, and the Foreign Commercial Service, June 7, 1984; 82.
      - Specter gets Senate subcommittee to order reopening of Pittsburgh Minority Business Office, June 7, 1984; 83.
      - Specter objects to federal highway funding cuts for PA, seeks restoration, June 8, 1984; 84.
      - Specter happy over ITC ruling that American steel hurt by foreign imports, June 13, 1984; 85.
      - Specter resolution designating October 7-13 as "National Birds of Prey Conservation Week" passes Senate, June 15, 1984; 86.
      - Specter wants Pittsburgh airport to retain "gateway" status for direct London flights, June 15, 1984; 87.
      - Specter urges $35 million for site preparation for Pittsburgh airport terminal, June 15, 1984; 88.
      - Concern for workers, says Specter, must be first concern in any sale of Conrail, June 19, 1984; 89.
      - Specter wins funding for runaway youth, job training, and health research programs, June 19, 1984; 90.
      - Specter cosponsors bill that would penalize states with laws which allow persons under 21 to purchase alcoholic beverages, June 20, 1984; 91.
      - Specter's plea for nuclear arms reduction summit meeting passed again by the Senate, June 20, 1984; 92.
      - Specter announces $44.3 million OSM grant to PA for reclaiming abandoned mine sites, June 21, 1984; 93.
      - Funding for PA projects, urged by Specter, included in defense budget, June 21, 1984; 94.
      - Specter tells State Committee he will fight for sale-leaseback legislation for elderly, June 21, 1984; 95.
      - Specter gets $6 million set aside in U.S. aid to El Salvador for judicial reform, June 21, 1984; 96.
      - Specter bill would set up Presidential Commission to study the effects of climate changes on agricultural production, June 22, 1984; 97.
      - Specter wins funding in Senate Appropriations Committee for runaway youth, job, and medical training programs, June 26, 1984; 98.
      - Specter amendments to budget reduction bill will save coal and iron ore industries $200 million over five years, June 28, 1984; 99.
      - Funding for Lock Haven and York flood control projects, sought by Senator Specter, approved by House-Senate conferees, June 26, 1984; 100.
      - Funding for Monongahela River, sought by Senator Specter, okayed by House-Senate conferees, June 26, 1984; 101.
      - Funding for Presque Isle project, sought by Senator Specter, okayed by conference, June 26, 1984; 102.
      - Specter saves state $62 million in highway funds; wins other funds for Pennsylvania, June 28, 1984; 103.
      - Specter tells House crime subcommittee his "career criminal" bill badly needed, June 28, 1984; 104.
      - Senator Specter to spend July congressional recess traveling across Pennsylvania, June 29, 1984; 105.
    - July-December 1984 (Box 1222, Folder 1)
      - Specter pledges commitment to permanent revenue sharing in 2pm speech today before PA borough mayors, July 9, 1984; 1.
      - Reaction of Specter to ITC recommendations on import relief for U.S. Steel industry, July 11, 1984; 2.
      - Specter bill would set federal standards for preventive detention of juveniles, July 23, 1984; 3.
      - Specter urges President Reagan to accept ITC recommendations on steel import quotas, July 23, 1984; 4.
      - Specter seeks ways to prevent future outbreaks of avian flu, July 24, 1984; 5.
      - Specter argues for end to diplomatic immunity for diplomats guilty of armed offenses, July 24, 1984; 6.
      - Funding cuts to farm programs, opposed by Specter, restored to agriculture budget, July 25, 1984; 7.
      - Specter wants $1.8 million for continued planning for Wyoming Valley flood control, July 25, 1984; 8.
      - Funding for central Pennsylvania projects, sought by Specter, okayed by appropriations subcommittee, July 25, 1984; 9.
      - Specter seeks technical assistance for Juniata county erosion project, July 26, 1984; 10.
      - Specter urges no cuts in M-1 tank production, July 30, 1984; 11.
      - Specter says War Powers Act must be amended to return power to declare war to congress, July 31, 1984; 12.
      - Specter bill would repeal cap on IDBs; says cap hurts PA and other state economies, August 1, 1984; 13.
      - Senate appropriations committee grants funding, sought by Specter, for coal research, and land and water conservation projects, August 1, 1984; 14.
      - Specter successful in getting U.S. Congress to order reopening of Pittsburgh Minority Business Office, August 2, 1984; 15.
      - Specter successful again in winning funding for food and shelter for the homeless, August 3, 1984; 16.
      - Specter asks nation's lawyers to become advocates for more federal funding to fight crime, August 3, 1984; 17.
      - Specter gets $1.8 million for continued planning for Wyoming Valley flood control, August 3, 1984; 18.
      - Specter defends President Reagan against Walter Mondale attack in Philadelphia, August 8, 1984; 19.
      - Specter strongly supports another effort to enact enterprise zone legislation, August 8, 1984; 20.
      - Specter urges VA to push for funding for Philadelphia VA medical center expansion, August 9, 1984; 21.
      - Specter amendment provides $20 million for job training for disadvantaged youth, August 9, 1984; 22.
      - Specter wins $570,000 for job re-training program for Johnstown, August 9, 1984; 23.
      - Specter again urges U.S. DOT to continue 80-20 ratio in funding for Johnstown's inclined plane, August 9, 1984; 24.
      - Specter urges funding be restored for overhaul of Lexington at Philadelphia shipyard, August 10, 1984; 25.
      - Senate provides funding for five Senator Specter initiatives: missing children, runaway and homeless children, OJJDP, prison construction, and local law enforcement, August 10, 1984; 26.
      - Specter asks President to declare flooded areas in Bedford and Somerset Counties in western Pennsylvania as "federal disaster areas", August 21, 1984; 27.
      - Specter urges nation's corrections professionals to become advocates for more federal funding for prison construction, August 22, 1984; 28.
      - Specter "gratified" by federal aid for flood-ravaged western PA, August 27, 1984; 29.